

Software Engineer

+1 (937) 623-9465 n.ren.estep@gmail.com renestep.com

A software engineer bringing over 4 years of experience in web-based application development. Coming from a fine arts and design background allows for excellent callaboration skills and different problem solving perspectives. Passionate about accessibility.

SKILLS

Essentials

 Public Speaking, Mentoring, Collaboration, Community Building

Programming Languages

 HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, SQL

Libraries & Frameworks

 ReactJS, NextJS, NuxtJS, Vue, SASS, Node, D3, Jekyll, Redux

Other Tools

 Postgres, MongoDB, Jest, Git, Axe accessibility Tools, Wave, Lighthouse, Docker, Adobe Creative Cloud

EDUCATION

2015 - Sinclair Community College

Dayton, Ohio
Web Programming Course Work

2012 - Wright State University

Dayton, Ohio
Computer science Course work

2011 - MFA - University of Tennessee

Knoxville, Tennessee
4D Media Concentation

2008 - BFA - Wright State University

Dayton, Ohio
Photography Concentration

EXPERIENCE

11/2017 - Present : Software Engineer - Mile Two, LLC

- Collaborated on and developed many projects utilizing ReactJS, Next.js, NodeJs, Python, Postgres and MongoDB.
- Introduced improvements to accessibility compliance through integrating Deque's axe-core wrapper on projects and eslint accessibility plugins to catch code that produces inaccessible applications.
- Mentored associate level and intern employees through pairing sessions and public presentations on accessibility and CSS skills.
- Collaborates with design and CSE teams for a more well rounded understanding of projects.

04/2017 - 11/2017 : Developer/Designer - MRS Electronic

- Design and produce iconography for mobile and desktop applications.
- Developed multiple projects using Javascript, AngularJS, CSS, Swift, and C#.

04/2016 - 04/2017 : Manager of Marketing & Creative Services - MRS Electronic

- Maintain website content
- · Design, produce, and schedule content for social media
- Design UI Wireframes

01/2015 - 05/2016 : Adjunct Instructor - Edison Community College

- Teaching and observing Introduction to Humanities.
- Covering art in all its forms while catering to an appreciation for education of creative natures.

CERTIFICATIONS

2020 - AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Expires December 2023
Amazon Web Services (AWS)

2017 - Legacy Front End Developer

No Expiration FreeCodeCamp